Can Demircan

cdemircan@tutanota.com

SKILLS

Programming: Python, R, MATLAB, Bash, HTML, CSS, JavaScript

Software and Tools: Git, \$\LaTeX\$, Markdown, Docker, Singularity, Continuous Integration

Languages: Turkish (native), English (fluent), German (beginner)

I am an MSc student in Neural & Behavioural Sciences, researching representation learning in humans and machines under the supervision of Dr. Eric Schulz in the research group Computational Principles of Intelligence located at the Max Planck Institute for Biological Cybernetics, Tübingen Germany.

Additionally, I am a certified instructor with the **Software Carpentry** and have taught workshops on different technical topics.

EDUCATION

MSc - Neural & Behavioural Sciences

University of Tübingen

2021 - 2023

- Thesis: Using tools of neuroscience to understand large language models: A case-study of temporal difference learning
- Member of the International Max Planck Research School for The Mechanisms of Mental Function and Dysfunction (IMPRS MMFD).

BA - Experimental Psychology

University of Oxford

2017 - 2020

- Thesis: How Task Relevance of Stimuli and Expectations Influence Visual Information Processing in the Human Brain
- · Graduated with 1st Class Honours

RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

Research Assistant - Computational Principles of Intelligence

Max Planck Institute for Biological Cybernetics

2021 - 2023

- Investigating representational basis of how humans learn in naturalistic tasks using online experiments and computational modelling
- · Supervised by Dr. Eric Schulz

Lab Rotation Student - Mental Health Mapping

Department of Psychiatry, University of Tübingen

2022 - 2023

- Investigated how brain structures of Social Anxiety Disorder patients differ from population norms using normative modelling
- · Supervised by Dr. Thomas Wolfers

Lab Rotation Student - Vision and Cognition Group

Centre for Integrative Neuroscience, Tübingen

2022

- Investigated how real and implied motion are processed in the human brain using fMRI
- Supervised by Prof. Dr. Andreas Bartels & Dr. Pablo Grassi

TEACHING EXPERIENCE

Software Carpentry – Version Control with Git University of Twente

2022

• Taught a one day workshop to PhD students on how to use Git

PUBLICATIONS & PREPRINTS

- **Demircan, C.**, Saanum, T., Pettini, L., Binz, M., Baczkowski, B. M., Kaanders, P., ... Schulz, E. (2023). Language Aligned Visual Representations Predict Human Behavior in Naturalistic Learning Tasks. arXiv preprint.
- **Demircan, C.**, Pettini, L., Saanum, T., Binz, M., Baczkowski, B. M., Doeller, C., ... Schulz, E. (2022). Decision-making with naturalistic options. In Proceedings of the Annual Meeting of the Cognitive Science Society (Vol. 44, No. 44).
- Senturk, Y. D., Ünver, N., **Demircan, C.**, Egner, T., & Günseli, E. (2023). The reactivation of task rules triggers the reactivation of task-relevant items. PsyArXiv preprint.